ISRAEL GUILLERMO

Olathe, Kansas 66061

Phone: 913-850-3510 | Email: israelguillermo22@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/israel-guillermo/ | GitHub: https://github.com/IsraelGuillermo | Portfolio: https://israelguillermo.github.io/#portfolio

SUMMARY

Software engineer with over eight years of experience in banking, insurance and business. Self-motivated, organized and fast learner with proven success in process improvement methodologies such as Lean Six Sigma. Skills include analytical thinking, creative problem solving, time management and communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL,

MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Applications:

PROJECTS

IntelliSup | GitHub: https://github.com/IsraelGuillermo/IntelliSup | Deployed Project: https://intellisup.herokuapp.com/

This program is the perfect application any of your supplier needs. The application is designed to allow user to make a new purchase order from suppliers. This order is then submitted into the database and displayed in the front end for the user to confirm information submitted. The application also allows the user to update tracking information and estimated ship date for each product.

- Tasks: Define tables using sequelize. Generate API routes to generate and derive information for table. Process to update, create and read information on database.
- HTML, CSS, Bulma, JQuery, JavaScript, Node.js, Handlebars, Heroku

NFL Teams | GitHub: https://github.com/lsraelGuillermo/project_01 | Deployed Project: https://israelguillermo.github.jo/project_01/

This project is a front-end program which is designed for football fans. The program allows the user to select their favorite NFL team from a drop-down menu. Once selected the program fetches the teams schedule and latest news using a 3rd party API. The user can then save this team as a favorite team.

- Tasks: Generate schedule for teams. This involves working with API and developing a responsive layout. Also contributed to the overall design of the website.
- HTML, CSS, Bulma, JQuery, JavaScript, API's, MySQL

Weather Dashboard | GitHub: https://github.com/lsraelGuillermo/weather_dashboard | Deployed Project: https://israelguillermo.github.io/weather_dashboard/

Weather Dashboard is an application which allows you to see the weather anywhere in the world! This application gives you the current weather, wind speed, humidity and UV index! The application also generates a 5-day forecast based on the city searched. Once a city is searched, a button is created and saved for user convenience.

- Developed whole application. Front end development using IMDB API.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, API's

EXPERIENCE

Service Consultant Farmers Insurance Group

2019 - 2020

Olathe, KS

Executed specialized project in analyzing and investigated insurance data which resulted in development of new documents and resources. Resolved escalated issues brought up by sales leaders, functional operational managers and agents. Reduced escalations and call volume by examining potential defects, collaborating with information technology to identify, monitor and resolve any system issues. Devised and achieved routing project for defects which resulted in reducing processing times and saving the company time and money.

Key Accomplishments:

Farmers LEAN Yellow Belt Certification

Senior Service Advocate Farmers Insurance Group

2015 - 2019

Olathe, KS

Coached and advocated for agents via phone with policy coverage and processing needs to reduce contacts to call center. Partnered with departments such as IT, Product and Legal to resolve escalated issues.

Bank Teller 2013 – 2015 Bank of America Lenexa, KS

Collaborated with team leader to correct and file paperwork daily. Ensured customer needs were met by assisting with transactions. Implemented a safe and essential closing procedure which outlined a safer way to close and secure bank documents.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Certificate: University of Kansas, Overland Park, KS A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Master's in Project Management: Colorado State University Global Campus Projected Graduation Date 05/29/22

Bachelor's in Business Administration: Mid-America Nazarene University Graduation Date 05/30/19